comprehension. College English Test,
Band 6, Part 2, Listening Comprehension.
Section A, Directions.
In this section, you will hear two long conversations.
At the end of each conversation, you will hear four questions.
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then, mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
centre. Conversation 1.
You're going to give a short speech of thanks for the speaker this evening, aren't
you, Bill? Yes.
You don't sound very enthusiastic.
It's not that bad, it?
No, I don't mind really, but I can never forget the first speech of thanks I did.
Why? What happened?
Well, I was in my early 20s.
I joined the Local History Society.
Yes. Anyway, I went along to a lecture by a Miss Bly.
Oh, do go on.
She was going to talk, with slides, about our town in the 18th century.
She'd just published a book on the subject, which was reckoned to be quite good.
So, I went along.
When I arrived, the secretary asked me if I could give the speech of thanks.
Rather stupidly, I said yes.
We've all done it.
Anyway, from that point on, I was scared.
What should I say?
I decided to make notes during the lecture and refer to interesting parts and thank
her on behalf of the Society.
In fact, by the time Miss Bly stood up to talk, I was feeling much better.
But she was so nervous that she kept forgetting what to say.
And she spoke almost in a whisper.
People at the back kept calling out, can't hear.
It was embarrassing.
can imagine it.
At least the slides were good.
That is, until the bulb in the projector blew and she had to finish the talk with no
illustrations. So what did you say in your speech of thanks?
What can you say?
You have to be polite.
I mentioned the interesting facts, referred to the excellent slides, and then
finished up by saying, we'd all like to thank Miss Bly for blowing us her slides.
Oh, no. I felt terrible.
I tried to apologize, not very successfully.
And the speech of thanks this evening?
I'll write down exactly what I'm going to say and read it carefully.
Questions one to four are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question one, what is the man asked to do this evening?
Question two, what do we learn about the man?
Question three, what does the man say about Miss Bly?
Question four, what does the man say about the first time he gave a speech of
thanks? Conversation two.
Another cup of tea, Paul?
No, thanks. Well, what's new, Laurie?
Nothing dramatic, but there's something you should know about.
What's that? Well, our rivals are offering extended credit terms to some of the
retailers in the Oh,
which rivals this?
only have two.
Barrett's company. Oh, them.
Well, they're hardly a threat.
I know they're smaller than us, but we can't afford to ignore them.
Yes, you're right, Laurie.
But I don't like extended credit.
It ties up cash we could put to better use elsewhere.
But I'll look into it on Monday.
Yes, and there's something else.
Don't tell me.
The letter from the tax revenue office?
Right. did you know?
Tara told me.
What's the problem?
Well, Tom got this letter late yesterday and then went frantic trying to find copies
of last year's accounts.
Did he find them?
No, and he was way before I could get hold of the letter.
How about a drive down to the office now?
And we'll see if everything's all right.
There's another reason why I wanted to chat with you before Monday.
I thought as much.
go on. me.
about selling that new motorcycle of yours in Indonesia?
What? You mean export?
Paul, I think you've been away too long.
This is jail motors.
We've never sold a bike abroad.
Don't worry, Laurie.
I'm not crazy.
I've been studying the possibility and I think we should give it a go.
It's not as easy as that though, is it?
We'd have to reorganize the whole company.
Don't be silly.
I don't intend starting next week.
We'll have to plan it properly.
And of course, there'll be a few problems.
A few problems?
I can see hundreds.
For one thing, transport.
I have enough trouble delivering bikes to shops only 40 miles away, never mind 5,000
miles. That's what forwarding agents are for.
Questions five to eight are based on the conversation you have just heard.
five. What does the woman think the man should know?
Question six. What does the woman think of Barrett's company?
Question seven. What did the woman say about the letter from the Tax Revenue Office?
Question eight. What is the man thinking of doing?
Section B. Directions.
this section, you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear three or four questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, You must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet one with a single line through
the centre. Passage one.
A report on sleep and nutrition released this month found that people who
consistently went to bed earlier than 11 p.m.
took in fewer calories and ate more healthy food.
In contrast, night owls who go to bed between 11 p.m.
and 3 a.m.
tend to consume more coffee, alcohol, refined sugars, and processed meats than early
risers. This report corresponds with the existing scientific literature on bedtime
and wellness. The relationship between getting more sleep and making better food
choices is well documented.
A study published last year in the American Journal of Nutrition found that people
who sleep more tend to eat less unhealthy food than their peers who don't get as
much rest. And a 2015 study from the University of California Berkeley found that
teens who go to bed late are more likely to gain weight over a five -year period.
As a group, night owl types tend to eat less healthy food and take in more calories
overall than early risers.
The later one goes to bed, the more calories one records the next day.
It is yet a challenge to explain the cause -and relationship between sleep and
nutrition. There may be a third factor that impacts both of them, or the
relationship could be reversed.
That is, people who eat less fall asleep earlier.
Still, if late sleepers want to lose a few pounds,
they can go to bed earlier than they usually do, thereby reducing their chances of
taking snacks before bedtime.
Questions nine to 11 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question nine, what do we learn about the report released this month?
Question ten, what does the study from the University of California Berkeley find
about teens who go to bed late?
Question 11, What should night owls do to reduce their consumption of unhealthy
food? Passage two,
researchers have found not just a diversity problem in Hollywood, but actually an
inclusion crisis. With less than a week before an Oscars ceremony that has already
been criticised for an all -white list of acting nominees, a study shows the film
industry does worse than television.
Just 3.4 of film directors were female, and only 7 of films had a cast whose balance
of race and ethnicity reflected the country's diversity.
When researchers looked at all TV shows, they also found that women of colour over
40 were regarded as largely invisible, and just 22 of TV series creators were
female. Overall, the study found half the films and TV shows had no Asian -speaking
characters, and more than one fifth of them had no black characters with dialogue.
The film industry still functions as a straight white boys club.
When looking at how women are depicted, the study found female characters were four
times more likely to be shown in sexy clothing, and nearly four times as likely to
be referred to as physically attractive.
But their results also indicated films and TV shows with women or people of colour
in the important jobs behind the scenes, director, producer or writer, tended to
have better diversity numbers.
Across TV and film, under -representation of non -white characters falls mostly on
Hispanics. Among more than 10,000 characters, proportions of white, black and Asian
characters came close to US population figures.
But Hispanics were just 5.8 of characters, despite being about 17
of the US population.
Question 13. What do we learn from the research?
Question 14. Who are regarded as largely invisible on TV shows?
Question 15. What does the speaker say about Hispanics?
Section C. Directions.
In this section, will hear three recordings of lectures or talks, followed by three
or four questions.
The recordings will be played only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D.
Then, mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
centre. Recording 1.
When purchasing life insurance, there are many important factors to consider.
One should buy the policies that give the most protection at the least cost, ensure
the right family members, and consider the family's financial needs.
It is important to buy the insurance from companies that are financially sound and
that are represented by honest, well -trained agents.
At various stages in a person's life, different kinds of life insurance are Probably
the only life insurance he needs is enough to cover his debts and burial expenses.
can be purchased at a lower rate during the young years, but by buying while young,
the premiums are paid in for a longer period of time.
In the end, the amount paid for premiums is about the same.
A person shouldn't buy insurance protection that really isn't necessary.
Suppose that Jerry marries Jeanette, who is a college graduate and is working.
Perhaps enough insurance would be needed to cover their debts and burial expenses.
Now, Jeanette has quit work, and their first child is on way.
They have purchased a home with a small down payment and a 30 -year mortgage.
The situation regarding life insurance takes on a different look.
There are dependents who need financial protection.
How much insurance is needed?
As the family increases in size, it is essential to add more insurance on the
breadwinner to protect the
dependents. When the children are young and depend upon the family for financial
needs, families with modest incomes have difficulty providing enough life insurance
to protect the mother and the children.
Families with modest incomes should ensure the breadwinner or breadwinners first.
When considering the amount of insurance for the mother with dependent children,
substitute child care is a need that should be planned for until the children can
care for themselves.
The death of a small child would have no effect upon the income of the family.
Perhaps a policy to meet funeral expenses would be sufficient for the young child,
although most people do not take out insurance on their young children.
As the children become financially independent of the family,
the emphasis on family financial security will shift from protection to saving for
the retirement years.
Every family situation is different, but it is important that each family give
adequate thought to planning its financial future.
Question 16 to 18 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 16, What life insurance should a single person buy according to the
speaker? Question 17,
What should people do as their family increases in size?
Question 18, When should one change their life insurance?
Recording 2. Stereotype may sound like a bad word, but there's nothing bad about it.
For one thing, stereotypes are often accurate.
When you ask people about their concept of stereotypes, they get it pretty much
right. Also, stereotypes are often positive, particularly of groups that we
ourselves belong to.
Some of the statistical generalisations may be positive, as some groups have
reputations for being smart, for being loyal,
for being brave, for all sorts of that are
wrong about stereotypes.
But there are problems with stereotypes.
For one thing, they are reliable insofar as they are based on unbiased samples.
But a lot of the information we get about human groups is through biased sources,
like how they are represented in the media.
And if these sources don't give you an accurate depiction, your stereotype won't be
accurate. For example, many Jews have been troubled by Shakespeare's depiction of
Shylock. If the only Jew you know is Shakespeare's Shylock, it's going to be a very
bad impression. So one problem with stereotypes is while we're good at drawing
conclusions from them, often our information isn't reliable.
second problem is that stereotypes, regardless of whether or not they're accurate,
can have a negative effect on the people that they apply to.
And this is what psychologist Claude Steele described as stereotype threat.
He has a vivid example of this.
Here's how to make African Americans do worse on a math test.
You have the test and you put on the test that they have to identify their race.
The very act of acknowledging that they're African American when given a test
ignites in them thoughts of their own stereotype,
which is negative regarding academics, and that makes them do worse.
Want to know how to make a woman do worse on a math test?
Same thing. Get her to write down her sex.
One recent study found a of clever twist on this.
When Asian American women are given a and they're asked to mark down their race,
they do better than they would otherwise do.
They're reminded of a positive stereotype that boosts their morale.
You ask them, on the other hand, to mark down their sex, they do worse because
they're reminded of a negative stereotype.
That's an example of how stereotypes have a potentially damaging effect on people.
Questions 19 to 22 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 19. What does the speaker say about stereotypes?
Question 20. What leads to the bias of stereotypes?
Question 21. What does the speaker say is a problem with stereotypes?
Question 22. What did one recent study find about stereotypes?
Recording 3. Sometimes when you take a common drug, you may have a side effect.
That is, the drug may cause some effect other than its intended one.
When these side effects occur, they are called adverse reactions.
Whenever you have an adverse reaction, you should stop taking the drug right away.
Ask your pharmacist whether he can suggest a drug that will relieve the symptoms but
that will not cause the adverse reaction.
If an adverse reaction to a drug is serious, consult your doctor for advice at once.
Drugs that are safe in the dosage stated on the label may be very dangerous in large
doses. example, aspirin is seldom thought of as dangerous, but there are many
reports of accidental poisoning of young children who take too many aspirin pills,
as well as the possible development of Ray's syndrome in children with the flu.
In adults, excessive use of some pain killing drugs may cause severe kidney damage.
Some drugs for relief of stomach upsets, when taken in excess,
can perhaps cause serious digestive problems.
You never use any over -counter drug on a regular continued basis, or in large
quantities, except on your doctor's advice.
You could be suffering from a serious illness that needs a doctor's care.
Each drug you take not only acts on the body, but may also alter the effect of any
other drug you are taking.
Sometimes this can cause dangerous or even fatal reactions.
For example, aspirin increases the blood thinning effects of drugs given to patients
with heart disease.
Therefore, a patient who has been taking such a drug may risk bleeding if he or she
uses aspirin for a headache.
Before using several drugs together, you should ask your doctor and follow his
advice. Your pharmacist can tell you whether certain drugs can safely be taken
together. Alcohol may increase the effect of a drug.
Sleeping pills combine with alcohol to produce a sleepy feeling.
When taking any drug, you should ask your doctor whether drinking alcohol could be
dangerous in combination with the medicine.
Experts believe there is a relationship between adult abuse of legitimate medicines
and the drug culture that has swept our country.
You can do your share to reduce the chances that your children will become part of
the drug culture by treating all medicines with respect.
Always let your children know that medicines and drugs should not be used
carelessly. Question 24.
What does the speaker say about alcohol drinking?
Question 25. What does the speaker call on parents to do at the end of the talk?
Question 26. does the speaker the
This is the end of listening comprehension.